(INDISTINCT CHATTERING)
It's on!
(CHILDREN LAUGHING)
(MARKET TRADERS SHOUTING)
BOY: Hurry up, you lot!
(ALL LAUGHING)
(LAUGHING)
MATURE JENNY: My first
Christmas in Poplar was unlike
any other I had known.
The streets, like all streets,
were strung with
coloured lights,
and children drew up lists,
like children everywhere.
As the days ticked down,
it seemed as though
the district was fizzing
with delight.
But at Nonnatus House,
a different magic was at work.
The sisters spent Advent
in prayer and meditation.
And the atmosphere was not
one of excitement,
but of expectant, joyous calm.
I wasn't entirely sure
what I should make of it.
I was young, and faith was
still a mystery to me.
(PHONE RINGING)
Nonnatus House,
midwife speaking.
It's me neighbour.
She started having pains.
Name, please?
Hilda Levons,
Lisbon Buildings.
You're meant to be sending her
down the hospital. She's
already crying her eyes out.
-(BABY CRYING)
-First one, she was in
labour for three days.
I'll come out and assess her.
Keep her tucked up
and warm till I get there.
(EXASPERATED SIGH)
It's all right, baby.
It's all right. Come here.
Mrs Levons was very anxious
at the last appointment.
I'll come with you
to reassure her,
and then go on to
the mastitis case.
Oh, straw for the crib.
Well done, Sister Monica Joan.
I availed myself of
the kindness of some customers
in the market.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
The spirit of the season
would appear to be amongst us.
(BICYCLE BELL RINGS)
(BABY CRYING)
Nurse!
You gotta come quick, Nurse!
Hurry, quickly!
She's in here. Come on!
She's through here.
-JULIENNE: Take that.
-Follow me. Please, hurry up.
(HILDA SCREAMING)
Hilda, it's all right.
The Nonnatans have come.
-You can stop pushing.
-I can't stop!
Let me through,
please, I'm a midwife.
HILDA: I need to go
to the hospital.
I had to have forceps
with the last one.
Second stage, Sister.
Don't distress yourself,
Hilda. All is well.
(MOANING)
Please, everybody,
stand right back so
we can assist Mrs Levons.
It might help if you
were dispersed elsewhere.
Begging your pardon.
This is a communal toilet,
and I was in the queue.
Get yourself down
the other bloody landing.
-I can't do this on my own!
-Yes, you can.
I want you to take
nice, steady breaths